<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Illicit Finance – Leveraging data to investigate illicit finance and the business networks behind crime and war</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leveraging data to investigate illicit finance and the business networks behind crime and war on Illicit Finance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:38:08 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the evidence for public ownership registries?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ubo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:25:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ubo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;While in New York, I asked a friend about his business in Florida and he explained to me that he is the owner through his Scandinavian business. Tracing his ownership structure would be time consuming and the task is made harder by the decision of the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) to annul public access to ownership registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CJEU ruled that public access contravenes the right to privacy in the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights. Implicit is the claim that evidence is weak to show that public ownership registries prevents crime. Or as my friend put it, the argument for public ownership data is a rehash of: &lt;it&gt;if you have nothing to hide you have nothing to fear&amp;quot;&lt;/it&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the court considers &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; evidence is unclear, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with the strongest case for public access to ownership registries, namely the practice of fighting illicit finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Panama Papers&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-panama-papers&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-panama-papers&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icij.org/investigations/panama-papers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Panama Papers&lt;/a&gt; is the most public exposure of the world&amp;rsquo;s most powerful people and their financial secrets and the impact that those leaks have had serves as an excellent example of the positive impact that public ownership data has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 11.5 million records exposed how politicians and criminals use the rogue offshore finance industry to launder money and avoid taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leaks implicated &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_people_named_in_the_Panama_Papers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;150 politicians from 50 countries&lt;/a&gt; and had serious political fallout as Iceland&amp;rsquo;s Prime Minister, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/apr/05/iceland-prime-minister-resigns-over-panama-papers-revelations&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sigmundur Davio Gunnlaugsson&lt;/a&gt;, was forced to resign from his office amid outrage that his family had sheltered money offshore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the revelations that caused snap elections in Iceland, the Guardian used the offshore leaks to shed light on the trail between Vladimir Putin and an offshore network of assets &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2016/apr/03/panama-papers-money-hidden-offshore&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;worth $2bn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigative journalists and their hard work not only helped close Mossack Fonseca, the infamous Panamanian law firm and target of the leak, but has also led to the prosecution of the firm&amp;rsquo;s owners, Lauria Paz and Ramon Fonseca who are defendants in a case in Panama where they are being tried for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.organojudicial.gob.pa/noticias/fijan-nueva-fecha-de-audiencia-para-celebrar-juicio-en-caso-conocido-como-panama-papers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;crimes against public economic order&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Lauria Pax and Ramon Fronseca operated Mossack Fronseca and how their crimes impacted ordinary people inspired &amp;ldquo;The Laundromat&amp;rdquo;, a film starring Meryl Streep and Gary Oldman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
.iframe {margin-top: 50px; margin-bottom: 50px}
&lt;/style&gt; 
&lt;iframe class=&#39;iframe&#39; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wuBRcfe4bSo?si=5R4jvk5i5q7k0q72&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Panama Papers show that transparent ownership is vital to fighting corruption and that when ownership structures are made public, those implicit in illicit finance face legal consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold on - is the Panama Papers really a strong case for opening ownership registries? After all, the trenche of 11 million documents are a leak of sensitive information from a shadowy organisation and not a register where ordinary people set up their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whistleblower nature of the Panama Papers is a perfectly valid objection, so let&amp;rsquo;s look at two investigations that used real ownership registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Open Lux Investigation&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-open-lux-investigation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-open-lux-investigation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transparency International has documented several cases where public access to beneficial ownership registries enabled journalists and activists to uncover corruption and money laundering. One of these cases is the &lt;a href=&#34;.https://www.occrp.org/en/openlux/&#34; &gt;OCCRP&amp;rsquo;s Open Lux Investigation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Open Lux investigation, journalists analysed beneficial owners registered in Luxembourg and found dozens of foreign citizens linked to corruption, embezzlement, and organised crime and, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://knowledgehub.transparency.org/assets/uploads/helpdesk/The-uses-and-impact-of-beneficial-ownership-information_2023.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Transparency International&lt;/a&gt; points out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;What sets the Open Lux Investigation apart from the Panama Papers is that, &lt;strong&gt;for the first time, journalists did not have to rely on leaks and, instead, relied on publically available data&lt;/strong&gt; to uncover hidden owners using Luxembourg companies to own assets and open bank accounts.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case of the Open Lux Investigation is a clear example of how actors other than law enforcement agencies are crucial to combating corruption and it is a role that the Court of Justice of the European Union recognise in &lt;a href=&#34;https://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=268059&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=lst&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=2425197&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;their ruling&lt;/a&gt; against public access to ownership registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Global Witness&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;global-witness&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#global-witness&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to identifying crime, actors are able to improve ownership data when that data is publically available. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globalwitness.org/en/campaigns/corruption-and-money-laundering/anonymous-company-owners/companies-we-keep/#chapter-0/section-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Global Witness&lt;/a&gt;, working with a group of volunteer data scientists at DataKind UK, analysed the UK&amp;rsquo;s beneficial ownership registries and successfully identified loopholes, information gaps and suspicous activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found that most companies registering their benenficial owners at the Persons of Significant Control registry in the UK, is straightforward, with an average of 1.13 beneficial owners for each UK company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of thousands of these companies file highly suspicious entries that would never have been found were it not for the open data nature of the register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Watch found common methods for avoiding disclosure of a company&amp;rsquo;s real owners such as disclosing an ineligible foreign company as the beneficial owner, filing a statement that the company has no beneficial owners, or creating circular ownership structures where a company control themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the companies with a foreign owner, 10,000 declare a foreign company as their beneficial owner and of these 72% are in a secrecy jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their analysis resulted in a red flagging system to uncover high risk entries and recommendations to the UK government demonstrating the benefit of open ownership registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public ownership data helps civl society, investigative journalists and law enforcement scrutinise data and combine it with other datasets, increasing the likelihood of spotting criminal activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is privacy an absolute right?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;is-privacy-an-absolute-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#is-privacy-an-absolute-right&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having established that open ownership data, in practice, helps us prevent crime, let&amp;rsquo;s scrutinise the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety about data protection is understandable, especially in consideration of companies like Facebook and Cambridge Analytica known for their exploitation of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand why my friend sides with the CEUJ and I think he made a good point when he said that open ownership data sounds like &amp;ldquo;if you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right to privacy is essential to our autonomy and it is important to respect privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, publishing information about who owns companies is different in one important respect, namely that as a business owner you are in the public sphere. As OpenOwnership&amp;rsquo;s Head of Policy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openownership.org/en/blog/who-owns-our-companies-why-privacy-isnt-always-in-the-public-interest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zosia Sztykowski&lt;/a&gt; explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Publishing information about who owns companies is fundamentally different. This is about chaning the role that companies play in society. We often forget that the legal form that we call a company can&amp;rsquo;t exist without the state, and agreements between states. Therefore, they have the right, and even the responsibibility to ensure that they serve a social good. Open ownership data can do just that. All while also providing desirable incentives for legitimate businesses, including reducing the risk of being exposed to bad actors and supporting the stability of economies globally.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy is a critical right, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a substantial ownership stake in a company gives that individual access to a range of benefits, including protection from personal liability.&lt;br&gt;
In exchange, is it not fair to expect business owners to help society ensure that companies are used for thier intended purposes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening a company is easy and benefits society as a whole and one unintened consequence of this is that corporations have become easy tools for criminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Zosia Stykowski explains, &amp;rsquo;there is a balance here to be struck between personal freedoms and the responsibility to create a fairer society.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also another important question when we invoke privacy and that is, who exactly are we trying to protect? Closing registries might protect more people with illegitimate intentions than those with legitimate intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the practice of investigating illicit finance teach us anything, it is that criminals thrive in secrecy. The decision to close access to ownership registries has impacted already scarce ownership data, forcing investigators to rely on leaked data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case for &amp;ldquo;protecting privacy&amp;rdquo; tries to safeguard against protecting the wrong people by assuming that those with &amp;ldquo;legitimate interest&amp;rdquo; have the right to access ownership registries. While well intended, this presumption has had negative consequences due to the lack of an EU-wide definition of &amp;ldquo;legitimate&amp;rdquo; intentions or circumstances&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Legitimate Interest&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;legitimate-interest&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#legitimate-interest&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CJEU ruling presumes that journalists and civil society organisations engaged in the prevention of money laundering have a legitimate interest and should be granted access to beneficial ownership information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absence of an EU-wide definition of &amp;ldquo;legitimate interest&amp;rdquo; has has effectively squashed the right of individuals and organisations with a legitimate interest to use the registers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journalists and civil society are unable to access 13 of 27 beneficial ownership registers in the EU, and after the court ruling, eight countries suspended public access to their registers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency International&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transparency.org/en/blog/eu-court-ruling-on-beneficial-ownership-registers-legitimate-accesshttps://www.transparency.org/en/blog/eu-court-ruling-on-beneficial-ownership-registers-legitimate-access&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt; is a useful resource to trace the impact of the ruling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
.ICJ_impact {margin-top: 40px; margin-bottom: 50px}
&lt;/style&gt; 
 &lt;iframe class=&#34;ICJ_impact&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;https://e.infogram.com/_/tHd7YTUogfgl5qIYJlZU?parent_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.transparency.org%2Fen%2Fblog%2Feu-court-ruling-on-beneficial-ownership-registers-legitimate-access&amp;src=embed#async_embed&#34;
&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;false&#34; tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries like Cyprus, Malta and the Netherlands have denied access, even if journalists and civil society demonstrate their legitimate access. Other countries require legitimate interest must be demonstrated on a case-by-case basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ireland&amp;rsquo;s approach is highly restrictive since you have to demonstrate that the beneficial owner under investigation is connected or convinced of an offence involving money laundering or terrorist financing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the goal of providing access to journalists and civil society is to help detect offences, the Irish approach seems to contravene this goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In trying to strike a balance between privacy and legitimate intentions, the CJEU has tipped the balance too far, which frustrates journalists and civil society investigations that yield tangible results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What the evidence tells us to do&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-the-evidence-tells-us-to-do&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-the-evidence-tells-us-to-do&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evidence from practice shows that open access is crucial to improving the quality of data in beneficial ownership registries and that public access prevents crime itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also clear that some members states will interpret the CJEU&amp;rsquo;s ruling conservatively and contravene the spirit of the CJEU ruling, namely to protect both privacy and civil society&amp;rsquo;s legitimate interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is required are EU rules that leave no space for discrimination against civil society and public watchdogs. Those rules should, instead, enable those who work with the combating of illicit finance to access crucial ownership data.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the meaning of illicit money?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_is_meaning_illicit_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:25:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what_is_meaning_illicit_money/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Despite substantial work from the United Nations, the World Bank, the IMF, OECD, and civil society, countries have been unable to reach a political consensus on the term &amp;ldquo;illicit&amp;rdquo; in illicit financial flows (IFFs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is customary in policy debates to distinguish between a narrow and a broad definition of IFFs. The former requires activities that are in breach of the law whereas the latter encompasses unethical acts that are deemed lawful, if unregulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distinction between the two policy camps leads to very different policy outcomes. Proponents of the narrow definition argue that transfers associated with tax evasion (illegal) qualify as IFFs while tax avoidance schemes (which comply with the law) do not even though they are unethical. In contrast, advocates of the broad definition argue that avoidance practices should still fall under the definition of illicit finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax evasion perfectly illustrates the difference between a broad and a narrow definition. This policy area is also a great example of how the narrow/broad definition is conceptually misleading. In reality, drawing the line between &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;illicit&amp;rdquo; is hard since illicit activities often involve illegal elements and require circumstantial interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Illicit finance through the lense of tax evasion and tax avoidance&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;illicit-finance-through-the-lense-of-tax-evasion-and-tax-avoidance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#illicit-finance-through-the-lense-of-tax-evasion-and-tax-avoidance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax evasion occurs when people or businesses deliberately do not pay tax that they legally owe by underreporting income, over-reporting expenses, or simply not paying taxes. In short, tax evasion encompasses the &amp;ldquo;hidden economy&amp;rdquo; in which people &amp;ldquo;conceal their presence or taxable income&amp;rdquo; (HM Treasury 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax avoidance involves &amp;ldquo;bending the rules of the tax system to gain a tax advantage that Parliament never intended&amp;rdquo;. The Result is compliance with the letter but not the spirit of the law. Those who engage in tax avoidance usually take advantage of technicalities for the purpose of reducing tax liability. This typically involves contrived agreements with the purpose of reducing tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In day-to-day reality, the distinction between tax avoidance and tax evasion is blurred as practices fall on a spectrum between tax avoidance and tax evasion. A case depend on its circumstances and legal assessment is seldom simple or obvious, which is whyit is hard to define tax avoidance as strictly illegal or illicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the narrow/broad definition debate unveils is not the illegal versus illicit dilemma, but uncertainty over the legal characterisation of tax arrangements as tax law has transitioned from detailed legal drafting to broad directives such as anti-abuse rules. In addition, the debate conceals the anxiety of policy-makers about the capacity of jurisdictions to enforce tax administration and prosecution if illicit finance is narrowly defined as &amp;ldquo;illegal activities&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A mixed approach&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;a-mixed-approach&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-mixed-approach&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A broad IFF agenda could be a powerful engine for systemic change. It would likely foster regulatory coordination and counter the tendency towards legal fragmentation. However, it is important that the broad definition focuses on law rather than ethics so as to avoid &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; interpretations of &amp;ldquo;illicit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One definition that lends itself to this ojbective is &amp;ldquo;unlawful&amp;rdquo; since this encompasses legal standards that go beyond fixed rules while still allowing for circumstantial legal assessment. Taking a broad approach would help conceptualise IFFs, though, for the purpose of measuring IFFs, more narrow legal definitions that define actors, transfer mechanisms, or origin are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is required, then, is a pragmatic approach that dissolves the IFF agenda into workable modules and indicators. A starting point is thematic areas set by existing IFF-related international initiatives followed by strategic alignment and collaboration between agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;International initiatives&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;international-initiatives&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#international-initiatives&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is already a rich repository of IFF-related international initiatives and strategic alignments that establish legal obligations to prevent illicit financial flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;United Nations Conventions against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances 1988 (Vienna Convention). This includes provisions on money laundering and international cooperation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime 2000 (Palermo Convention).
This requires countries to criminalise money laundering, and includes frameworks for extradition, mutual legal assistance and law enforcement cooperation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Convention for the Suppression of the Financing of Terrorism 1999 – requires states to criminalise the financing of terrorism, and adopt powers to freeze and seize funds intended to be ued for terrorist activities.
-United Nations Convention against Corruption 2003 (Merida Convention) – requires measures to revent and criminalise corruption, provide international cooperation and asset recovery on corruption cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition a number of UN Security Council Resolutions have introduced measures to counter illicit financial flows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2030 Addis Adaba Action Agenda emphasises combating illicit financial flows to safeguard public resources essential to financing Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What these initiatives point to are themes of different activities that constitute illicit finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Activities associated with illicit finance&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;activities-associated-with-illicit-finance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#activities-associated-with-illicit-finance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Below are the most frequently cited activities associated with illicit finance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax evasion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money laundering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terrorist financing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fraud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conflict financing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counter-terrorist financing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smuggling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trafficking drugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People or wildlife smuggling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financing of organised crime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counterfeitings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tax avoidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recap&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#recap&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The absence of an agreed defininition makes developing methodologies for monitoring and assessing illicit financial flows difficult, and where methodologies exist, disagreements and dissatisfaction with methods stem from this lack of conceptual clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One policy space affected by the lack of conceptual clarity is the 2030 Addis Adaba Action Agenda and its emphasis on combating illicit financial flows to safeguard public resources essential to the financing of Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Without a clear definition, policy makers find it hard to set strategic objectives let alone measure &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; in safeguarding public resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrow/broad definition of illicit finance has dominated the policy debate. This distinction is alluring but misleading as activities often fall on a spectrum between illicit and illegal. Instead, the debate should focus on dividing illicit finance into modules with a broad definition for strategic definitions and a narrow definition reserved for projects that aim to measure illicit finance.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three steps in sanctions research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three_steps_sanctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three_steps_sanctions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;We often talk about sanctions in the context of efficiency or individual cases. Who&amp;rsquo;s who in the sanctions space has, as a result, become elusive when there are characteristics, data sets, and methods of revealing sanctioned entities and their networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets explore three common steps in the research process behind investigations in the space of anti-money laundering solutions, from the the design of research methods to the collection and analysis of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;steps ml-4 mb-12 border-l border-gray-200 pl-6 dark:border-neutral-800 [counter-reset:step]&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Research Design&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;research-design&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#research-design&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Ontology&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;ontology&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ontology&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The firt step in researching who&amp;rsquo;s who in the sanctioned space is knowing how to describe entities and relations beetween them. In industry, we describe our domain and its objects in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ontology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ontology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ontology is a formal naming and definition of categories, properties, and relations betweeen concepts, data, or entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend using the Follow the Money&amp;rsquo;s ontology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow the Money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the Money is an ontology that is commonly used in anti-corruption investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their ontology defines entities revelant in such investigations, like people or companies, and helps investigators create a graph of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common tasks for an investigative reporter is to work out if one thing is the same as another. Is the person who owns a sanctioned company the same guy who is a mayor in my city?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many facts might provide hints that allow us to establish if he is &amp;ldquo;our guy&amp;rdquo;. Do the individuals have the same name, date of birth, nationality, passport number? Do we know about links to other individuals or companies in both data sets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a clearly defined ontology, you can turn representations of objects and events into complex data and compile and cross-reference these hints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Follow the Money ontology consists of schemata ie object types that exist as an inheritance hieracy, rooted in things and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things&lt;/strong&gt; describe real-world objects like &lt;code&gt;people&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Companies&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Assets&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Court Cases&lt;/code&gt;. You can think of things as entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intervals&lt;/strong&gt; are &lt;code&gt;business interests&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;court cases&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sanctions&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;transactions&lt;/code&gt; and are useful for linking entities together, possibly over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is an interactive graph view of FMT ontology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://service.tib.eu/webvowl/#iri=https://alephdata.github.io/followthemoney/ns/ftm.xml&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; height=&#34;500px&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; title=&#34;Interactive Schema of FMT ontology&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have an ontology that structures your domain and its objects and relations, you can build a taxonomy to describe and group your information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build a taxonomy&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;build-a-taxonomy&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#build-a-taxonomy&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While an ontology is a formal representation of knoweldge that defines concepts and relationships within a domain in a structured way, a taxonomy concerns the classification of entities based on their characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomies are used to group types of entities into categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, when we talk about associations and relationships in the sanctions space, we need ways of describing the type of entity or relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An associated entity could be an entity type: person, organisation, or vessel. If we know that our entity is a person, we can class his or her relationship to the sanctioned entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxonomy of relationships&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Relationship&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Definition&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Example&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Employee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The associated person is employed by the sanctioned individual&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A nuclear engineer working for sanctioned company&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Owned or controlled by&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The associated organisation is owned or controlled by the entity it is connects with&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OO NOVATEK-PERM is a subsidiary that is owned by sanctioned OAO NOVATEK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Family member&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An associate is a spouse, uncle, aunt, child, parent of sanctioned person&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Asma al-Assad is the spoise od Bashar al-Assad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a taxonomy is crucial to investigations. A good taxonomy lets investigators describe and filter the information they&amp;rsquo;re collecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collect data&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;collect-data&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#collect-data&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global sanctions regimes vary as some countries implement and enforce the sanctions of international organisations such as the EU and the UN while others develop their own sanctions programs with their own sanctions lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in researching sanctioned entities is knowing which ones appear on an official sanctions list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Key sanctions lists&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;key-sanctions-lists&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#key-sanctions-lists&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Government and finanical authorities maintain targeted sanctions lists. These lists are often available online and the lists evolve quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UN sanctions list&lt;/strong&gt; is also known as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/securitycouncil/content/un-sc-consolidated-list&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UNSC Consolidated List&lt;/a&gt;. It consists of one list of individual targets and one list of entities and group targets. UN sanctions are imposed by UN security council resolutions when the council determines a country is in breach of international law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are the most influential global sanctions regime and consists of multiple sanctions lists. The Office of Foreign Assets Control, OFAC, maintains its primary sanctions lists.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://sanctionslist.ofac.treas.gov/Home/SdnList&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Specially Designated Nationals (SDN)&lt;/a&gt; list sanctions individuals and companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://sanctionslist.ofac.treas.gov/Home/ConsolidatedList&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Consolidated Sanctions List&lt;/a&gt; contains sanctions information not included in the SDN list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UK sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are enforced by the Office of Financial Sanctions Implementations (OFSI) and Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Treasury (HTM). Accordingly, UK firms must screen against UK Sanctions List.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Australia sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are implemented by the Australian Sanctions Office (ASO) and the Department of Foriegn Affairs and Trade (DFAT). These two deparments implement Australia&amp;rsquo;s sanctions regime and firms must screen against Consolidated List of sanctions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canada sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are implemented under the Special Economic Measures Act (SEMA) and the Justice for Victims of Corrupt Foreign Officials Act (JVCFO). Canadian sanctions are on the [Consolidated Canadian Autonomous Sanctions List].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japan sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are issued under the authority of the Foreign Exchange and Foreign Trade Act (FEFTA) and implemented by the Ministry of Economy, Trade, and Industry and the Ministry of Finance. Japan works with the UN, the US, and the EU in compiling its sanctions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China sanctions&lt;/strong&gt; are issued by the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs and, since 2020, China&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Commerce has developed new sanctions regulations designed as a response to Western sanctions. In China, there is the Unreliable Entity List (UEL) and rules the Anti-Foreign Sanctions Law and the Blocking Rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Data in key sanctions lists&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;data-in-key-sanctions-lists&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#data-in-key-sanctions-lists&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sanctions lists are useful primary sources. They help investigators identify who&amp;rsquo;s who in the sanctions space and serve as an excellent stepping stone to identifying associates and enablers of sanctioned entities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common information about sanctioned entities include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nationality&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;passport number&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;country of birth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;reason for being sanctioned&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctions lists are usually strucuted xml, csv or html format, but can come as unstructured pdfs that require manual extraction. Below is an extract from the UNSC Consolidated List.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iTAi.007 Name: 1: ABDUL LATIF 2: MANSUR 3: na 4: na
Name (original script): عبد اللطيف منصور
Title: Maulavi Designation: Minister of Agriculture under the Taliban regime DOB: Approximately 1968 POB: Zurmat District, Paktia Province, Afghanistan Good quality a.k.a.: a) Abdul Latif Mansoor b) Wali Mohammad Low quality a.k.a.: na Nationality: Afghanistan Passport no: na National identification no: na Address: na Listed on: 31 Jan. 2001 ( amended on 3 Sep. 2003, 18 Jul. 2007, 21 Sep. 2007, 13 Feb. 2012, 18 May 2012, 22 Apr. 2013 ) Other information: Taliban Shadow Governor for Logar Province as of late 2012. Believed to be in Afghanistan/Pakistan border area. Belongs to Sahak tribe (Ghilzai). Review pursuant to Security Council resolution 1822 (2008) was concluded on 27 Jul. 2010. INTERPOL-UN Security Council Special Notice web link:https://www.interpol.int/en/How-we-work/Notices/View-UN-Notices-Individuals click here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data points present in sanctions lists are important points of reference. Investigators can use data points like alias and age or passport number to confirm if the person on the sanctions list is the same as the person in a company register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Limit of primary sources&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;limit-of-primary-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#limit-of-primary-sources&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investigating if an individual, vessel, or organisation is subject to financial sanctions is relatively straightforward. You usually return a match after a quick search on one of the sanctions lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job of investigating is harder when we want to identify associates or entities enabling the sanctioned person or organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, identifying if an entity is sanctioned becomes harder when shell companies are involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A  company may not show up as sanctioned on sanctions lists, but if a sanctioned entity owns 51% of the company then both the company and the sanctioned entity are sanctioned. This is the OFAC50 rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctions lists are excellent primary sources but investigations require a holistic approach. For this, we turn to other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Data Enrichment&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;data-enrichment&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#data-enrichment&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use othersources as part of investigations to enrich the data we collect from sanctions lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources commonly used in investigations range from ownership and land registries to leaked documents, mentions in media, and aggreggated data in databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excellent example of how investigators draw on open sources is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebureauinvestigates.com/stories/2024-05-10/leaked-documents-reveal-abramovichs-ongoing-vitesse-connection/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;investigation&lt;/a&gt; into Roman Abramovich and his financial dealings with the Dutch football club, Vitesse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roman Abramovich was subjected to UK and EU sanctions following Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using the Oligarch Files, a cache of leaked data originating from MeritServus, an offshore service provider based in Cyprus, investigators at the Bureau of Investigative Journalism (TBIJ) and the Guardian were able to reveal that Roman Abramovich, who then owned Chelsea football club, was the source of all money used to fund the Dutch football club, Vitesse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guardian found that Abramovich had covertly funded the 2010 acquisition of Vitesse Arnhem via a network of offshore entities before channelling at least 117 million euros to the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebureauinvestigates.com/stories/2023-03-29/roman-abramovich-bankrolled-major-dutch-club-while-chelsea-owner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the  Oligarch Files helped investigators enrich the data they already had on Abramovich, leading them to identify 6 companies associated with Abramovich and Vitesse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Entity Resolution&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;entity-resolution&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#entity-resolution&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In AML and illicit finance, we are always striving toward a source of truth. We enrich our data in the hopes of getting to that truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enriching data requires that investigators perform entity resolution to ensure that they are correctly linking records together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enity resolution is broadly speaking the process of identifying data records in a source across multiple sources that refer to the same entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can resolve entities manually, usually by looking at the similarity of their names, age, height, and other data points. As you read these records, you understand if the sources describe the same two peope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re certain the records match, you can merge the records and enrich  your entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manually resolving entities is a time-consuming task, so investigators naturally rely on data science to combine records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of data, entity resolution or record matching also goes by the name of some of its techniques, like fuzzy matching, merge purge, data matching or idenity resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through entity resolution, we can identify if two records refer to the same entity and enrich our understanding of that data. Once we have a source of truth, the next step is understanding how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Network Analysis&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;network-analysis&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#network-analysis&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data dumps are rarely useful on thier own and the process of collecting, enriching and resolving data should yield a big set of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network analysis is one of the techniques that investigators can use to extract useful information from big data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This useful information teaches us about network risks and broader trends in how illict finance is organised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the investigation into Roman Abramovich, investigators identfied 6 companies associated with him and the football club Vitesse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://embed.kumu.io/7839eb07b6212cd1cdbe0acb1267f260#untitled-map&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500px&#34; class=&#39;iframe&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By drawing the connections between these entities, we learn who&amp;rsquo;s connection to whom and how sanctioned individuals like Roman Abramovich use offshore networks to circumvent sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recap&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#recap&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every investigation requires four simple steps to be successful. Before you start, you should decide on a way of first describing objects and relations and then set up a system of classifying these objects. Once ready, start by identifying and collecting information from reliable sources, then, branch out by collecting data from as many relevant sources as possible. Use entity resolution to match records and find useful insights in your data with network analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Good Coverage in Adverse Media with a Source Typology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/adverse_media_taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/adverse_media_taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Adverse Media, also known as negative news screening, requires that companies identify risks associated with a company or individual in media. Traditionally, compliance officers use Google and keyword searches to find articles, but this process has largely been automated by machine learning models that can identify risks in thousands of articles online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explosion in the number of articles that companies process has led to confusion in the compliance industry as to what we mean by &amp;ldquo;good coverage&amp;rdquo; when we talk about adverse media. People fall back on quantity as a measure of good coverage when they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t since adverse media is associated with high levels of noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many sources are simply not relevant and one provider that I reviewed braged about scraping 200,000 domains. Among these domains were recipe blogs. Part of the reason why we don&amp;rsquo;t have a definition of &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; in adverse media is because there is no standard way of describing sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll share with you how I designed an adverse media typology and why you should focus on the relevance of your adverse media sources rather than their percieved reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Typology of sources in adverse media&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;typology-of-sources-in-adverse-media&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#typology-of-sources-in-adverse-media&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My task as a researcher on Comply Advatange&amp;rsquo;s adverse media team was to build a typology that would help us communicate the sources we cover to clients. Our adverse media typology had to explain why we selected those specific sources and not &amp;ldquo;everything&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below is the result of iterations with clients and regulatory affairs and it serves as an example of how we can define sources in the world of adverse media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Typology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;International newspaper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;News websites, news aggregators, online websites, international newspapers published in more than one language and distributed in more than one country.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;National newspaper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A newspaper distributed in one country.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Regional &amp;amp; local newspaper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A newspaper distributed in a city or region&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Judicial authority&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Any soure extracted from a court or judicial ministry website.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Police authoriy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A source extracted from police department or ministry. For example, police blotters or watch press release.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Public authority&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A source extracted from a public authority or international organisation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Industry or professional blogs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A blog or company website published by a professional or company&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The legal research behind the typology&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-legal-research-behind-the-typology&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-legal-research-behind-the-typology&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The taxonomy is based on best practices rather than regulatory requirements. What I found from legal research and from working with our regulatory affairs team is that adverse media regulatory requirements are broad and pretty similar regardless of country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulatory requirements do not provide by design a clear definition of what sources an AML officer should cover and I noticed this in client calls since clients themselves rarely could tell &amp;ldquo;what sources&amp;rdquo; they really want. The benefit of working in a regulatory landscape with broad definitions is that it gives you freedom to shape and optimise your typology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of strict regulatory requirements, I turned to industry recommendations of best practices to determine what &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; is in adverse media. One organisation that publishes best practices is the Wolfsberg Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Best Practices&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;best-practices&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#best-practices&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In their recommendations, the Wolfsberg Group outline a clear preference for international, national, and regional newspapers in order of prefence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They mention in their report that compliance officers should rely on news agencies and national newspapers since they provide higher quality reporting and editorial oversight. These sources provide content that is corroborated and edited by network participants. The Wolfsberg Group lists regional and local newspapres as useful since they report on events which are not covered by large scale outlets but note that these sources can often be less reliable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the typology is not a ranking sources&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;why-the-typology-is-not-a-ranking-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#why-the-typology-is-not-a-ranking-sources&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction to the Wolfsberg Group was to build a typology surrounding the concept of reliability, placing public, judicial, and government sources as the most reliable sources followed by newspapers and blogs. However, while meeting with clients I learnt that prioritising certain sources opens up the trap door to quanity over quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question that clients would have after discussing our coverage would almost without exception be something along the lines of: &amp;ldquo;so why can&amp;rsquo;t we have more judicial sources?&amp;rdquo; The answer is usually that there are only so many courts in a country. Instead of ranking sources, I thought of building the taxonomy around the concept of relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aim for relevancy rather than strict reliability&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;aim-for-relevancy-rather-than-strict-reliability&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#aim-for-relevancy-rather-than-strict-reliability&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Wolfsberg group recommends international and national newspaper, their concern is with big corporations that rank high on Google. This is because they keep keyword searches in mind. What you want to achieve with a machine learning approach is to cover what is most relevant on Google and retrieve  the pages that a simple keyword won&amp;rsquo;t find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you cast adverse media as a search optimised (SOE) ice berg, having a simple but well defined typology becomes really valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typology allows us to demonstrate the relevancy of our sources. It helps us show clients that we cover the tip of the ice berg by which I mean the domains that rank high on Google. We can then point to the sources below the tip, those sources that we curate and which an AML officer would likely miss with a simple keyword search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recap&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#recap&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adverse Media is full of noise and because the industry has yet to come to terms with what we mean by &amp;ldquo;good media coverage&amp;rdquo;, the focus remains on quantity rather than cutting through the noise. With the help of a typology of sources in Adverse Media, we can pivot the conversation and discuss &amp;ldquo;relevancy&amp;rdquo;. This way, the industry can ask whether an AML provider curates relevant sources in addition to what ranks highest on Google.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking networks on Telegram with Groupint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/groupint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/groupint/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/groupintgraph.png&#34; title=&#34;Graph of networks on Telegram&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Graph of networks on Telegram&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Telegram has become popular for threat actors to engage in illicit activity. These actors range from simple fraudsters to cybercriminals and Russian military and intelligence personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram is popular because of its end-to-end encrypted messaging, yet, the platform is not as anonymous as users believe. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s a rich repository of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigators can use this information to identify networks on Telegram and connect who&amp;rsquo;s talking to whom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groupint is a recent OSINT tool investigators can use to invesigate networks on Telegram. I helped develop this tool as part of the R&amp;amp;D team at OSINT for Ukraine and in this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how we built an app that lets users see who&amp;rsquo;s talking to whom on Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Groupint?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-groupint&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-groupint&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groupint is an app that enables investigators to scrape data from Telegram groups and connect users through an intuitive and visually appealing graph and user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app is an open-source tool developed by OSINT for Ukraine, an independent non-profit foundation dedicated to using open-source intellgience to investigate war crimes in relation to the Russo-Ukrainian War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groupint enables investigators to analyse networks within specific Telegram communities by scraping users and connecting who&amp;rsquo;s who in a graph database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify all the users and who they&amp;rsquo;re talking to, simply input the name of a group that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in and the app extracts all of the users and the groups that they are part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groupint enables network analysis and opens up a host of opportunities. Investigators can identify threat actors and their networks. They can also map trends in how illicit finance and threat actors interact with social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might wonder how it is possible to scrape and connect users between groups in an end-to-end encrypted app that supposedly provides you with unprecedented anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple; Telegram data is routinely sold in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Telesint&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;telesint&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#telesint&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Groupint is powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://telesint.dev/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Telesint&lt;/a&gt;, a database of over 3 million open Telegram chats and tens of thousands of private chats. Their bot is designed to search for people in open and closed Telegram groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Telesint doesn&amp;rsquo;t collect &amp;ldquo;personal data&amp;rdquo;, the bot collects enough data points to link users from different groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; - user&amp;rsquo;s unique id&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;label&lt;/code&gt;- user&amp;rsquo;s alias&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;group&lt;/code&gt; - a list of Telegram groups that user is a member of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;last-of-type:mb-0 rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2 mt-4 group&#34; &gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;flex items-center cursor-pointer select-none list-none p-1 rounded transition-colors hover:bg-gray-100 dark:hover:bg-neutral-800 before:mr-1 before:inline-block before:transition-transform before:content-[&#39;&#39;] dark:before:invert rtl:before:rotate-180 group-open:before:rotate-90&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong class=&#34;text-lg&#34;&gt;Click me to reveal example of user data&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;p-2 overflow-hidden&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code&#34;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34; data-lang=&#34;json&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;id&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;94252564&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;label&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;andrey600&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;username&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;andrey600&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;group&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;chat_massovka&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;silovikigroup&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;mesles&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;        &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;komsomolka_ru&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;err&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;button
      class=&#34;code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50&#34;
      title=&#34;Copy code&#34;
    &gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden copy-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Architecture&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#architecture&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The architecture behind Groupint is straightforward. Our user logs in to Groupint, our streamlit app. The group that the user queries is communicated to Telesint using a python library called &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.telethon.dev/en/stable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Telethon&lt;/a&gt;. This library is crucial. We use it to connect to Telesint and scrape results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/architecture_groupint.png&#34; title=&#34;Groupint Architecture&#34; alt=&#34;architecture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Groupint Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results are stored in a Neo4j database, which we use to draw connections between individuals in different groups in a graph that outlines each network present on Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/groupintgraph.png&#34; title=&#34;Groupint Architecture&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Groupint Architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get started&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#get-started&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Acquire API Credentials&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;acquire-api-credentials&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#acquire-api-credentials&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you log in to Groupint, you  set up a session with Telesint to access data on Telegram groups. Creating a session requires that you provide the phone number linked to your Telegram account and your Telegram API id and API hash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquire the API id and API hash from Telegram. You need to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign up to &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/api/obtaining_api_id&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to your Telegram account &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.telegram.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got to &amp;ldquo;API development tools&amp;rdquo; section and fill out the form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will get your API id and API hash parameters required for user authorization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the moment, each number can only have one api id connected to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#prerequisites&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have installed on your system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker to compose the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 3.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poetry to install python dependencies and set up your virtual environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Clone project and start containers&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;clone-project-and-start-containers&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#clone-project-and-start-containers&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clone the Groupint project from the OSINT for Ukraine Github accoun and run docker-compose or docker compose to set up the project .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/OSINT-for-Ukraine/groupint.git
cd groupint
docker-compose up&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;button
      class=&#34;code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50&#34;
      title=&#34;Copy code&#34;
    &gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden copy-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set your login credentials. Create a secrets.toml file inside the streamlit folder and set your password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Create secrets file 
cd streamlit 
touch secrets.toml
# Set password variable
password = &amp;#34;xxxx&amp;#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;button
      class=&#34;code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50&#34;
      title=&#34;Copy code&#34;
    &gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden copy-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Run a local instance of Groupint&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;run-a-local-instance-of-groupint&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#run-a-local-instance-of-groupint&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can start your local instance of Groupint and run the app locally with the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;code-block relative mt-6 first:mt-0 group/code&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;streamlit run interface.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;opacity-0 transition group-hover/code:opacity-100 flex gap-1 absolute m-[11px] right-0 top-0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;button
      class=&#34;code-copy-btn group/copybtn transition-all active:opacity-50 bg-primary-700/5 border border-black/5 text-gray-600 hover:text-gray-900 rounded-md p-1.5 dark:bg-primary-300/10 dark:border-white/10 dark:text-gray-400 dark:hover:text-gray-50&#34;
      title=&#34;Copy code&#34;
    &gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;group-[.copied]/copybtn:hidden copy-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:block success-icon pointer-events-none h-4 w-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
