<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Illicit Finance – </title>
    <link>http://localhost:44379/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Illicit Finance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:38:08 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:44379/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are ownership registries evidence-based?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44379/posts/ubo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 18:25:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:44379/posts/ubo/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;While in New York, I asked a friend about his business in Florida and he explained that he is the owner through his Scandinavian business. Tracing his ownership structure would be time consuming and the task is made harder by the decision of the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) to annul public access to ownership registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CJEU ruled that public access contravenes the right to privacy in the EU Charter of Fundamental Rights. Implicit is the claim that evidence is weak to show that public ownership registries prevents crime. Or, as my friend put it, the argument for public ownership data is a rehash of: &lt;it&gt;if you have nothing to hide you have nothing to fear&amp;quot;&lt;/it&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the court considers &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; evidence is unclear, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with the strongest case for public access to ownership registries, namely the practice of fighting illicit finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Panama Papers is likely the most widely recognised case of what happens when ownership data is publically exposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The reality of ownership data&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-reality-of-ownership-data&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-reality-of-ownership-data&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Is privacy an absolute right?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;is-privacy-an-absolute-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#is-privacy-an-absolute-right&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public ownership data helps civl society, investigative journalists and law enforcement scrutinise data and combine it with other datasets, increasing the likelihood of spitting criminal activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having established that open ownership data, in practice, helps us prevent crime, let&amp;rsquo;s scrutinise the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anxiety about data protection is understandable, especially in consideration of companies like Facebook and Cambridge Analytica known for their exploitation of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand why my friend sides with the CEUJ - the right to privacy is essential to our autonomy and it is important to respect privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, publishing information about who owns companies is different. As OpenOwnership&amp;rsquo;s Head of Policy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openownership.org/en/blog/who-owns-our-companies-why-privacy-isnt-always-in-the-public-interest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zosia Sztykowski&lt;/a&gt; explains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Publishing information about who owns companies is fundamentally different. This is about chaning the role that companies play in society. We often forget that the legal form that we call a company can&amp;rsquo;t exist without the state, and agreements between states. Therefore, they have the right, and even the responsibibility to ensure that they serve a social good. Open ownership data can do just that. All while also providing desirable incentives for legitimate businesses, including reducing the risk of being exposed to bad actors and supporting the stability of economies globally.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy is a critical right, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a substantial ownership stake in a company gives that individual access to a range of benefits, including protection from personal liability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In exchange, is it not fair to expect business owners to help society ensure that companies are used for thier intended purposes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening a company is easy and benefits society as a whole. The unintended consequence is that this has made corporations easy tools for criminals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a balance here to be struck between personal freedoms and the responsibility to create a fairer society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, privacy invokes a claim to protection but never answers who we are trying to protect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defense implies that &amp;ldquo;evidence that public ownership data prevents crime is weak&amp;rdquo;. There is likewise no evidence that closed ownership data protects more people with legitimate intentions than people with illegitimate intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Impact of the Decision&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-impact-of-the-decision&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-impact-of-the-decision&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to harvest users from Telegram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:44379/posts/where_find_ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:44379/posts/where_find_ownership/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;How is social media used in OSINT investigations?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;how-is-social-media-used-in-osint-investigations&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#how-is-social-media-used-in-osint-investigations&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is Telegram?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-telegram&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-telegram&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why scrape users?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;why-scrape-users&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#why-scrape-users&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Steps to harvesting users from Telegram&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;steps-to-harvesting-users-from-telegram&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#steps-to-harvesting-users-from-telegram&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is Telesint?&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-telesint&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-telesint&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Neo4j - what is is and why it&amp;rsquo;s powerful&lt;span class=&#34;absolute -mt-20&#34; id=&#34;neo4j---what-is-is-and-why-its-powerful&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#neo4j---what-is-is-and-why-its-powerful&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
